Once we have specification document, we
can ask AI to formulate those specs. But
it's very hard for humans to express um
intent in the words cause of context
>> with AI. Once you go deep down enough
and things get complicated, I think at
that point there's a ton of context that
is needed and understanding of code
flow.
>> I started with creating markdown tasks
manually. The problem with that it was a
huge context and I will not have good
success rate and it would be very hard
to roll back. You use chat GBT, you use
cloud desktop, whatever. They have
memory, they have conversational memory.
But that's not the case for the models,
right? AI have APIs.
>> So, we need to continue that context. We
send that context [music] back to it
every time.
>> Yeah.
>> The biggest benefit of the spec because
it is readable, we can actually review
it. Yes,
>> it's different from tests that we
theoretically also could declare a
source of truth and review it instead of
specs. But as we spoke, we don't want to
read anyone else's code and especially
the nontechnical people that they even
cannot.
>> Yeah,
>> spec is different. Yeah.
>> Because it's readable in your language.
There are hundred of languages
translations of gear and spec. You can
read it in udo if you feel like
>> and and this is suddenly something that
everybody um around the table
>> can sync on.
>> Yeah.
>> And say okay now we can read the spec.
>> It's not painful and English and we can
verify that what's in the spec it's
actually what we want it to be generated
from on pro.
>> Yeah.
>> Now if it's not we go back and forth. we
iterate until it is or we just fix the
spec. It's it's almost plain language
>> and and presumably you could almost like
use LLM as a judge as well to some
extent almost to as a as a as a final
backup to say look because because
people are going to be lazy, right? And
and I think this is one of those
interesting things where even if you
look at something like code review,
>> okay, people don't like looking at each
other's like at someone else's code for
example, but it's something that um the
more text, the more change there is,
we'll kind of like look at that and go,
"Yeah, that that kind of like looks
good. If there's two lines, we're going
to we're going to be questioning the
variable choices and [laughter] things
like that." Right? So if there is going
to be a big set of tests or a big
specification, are we actually going to
go through it? So imagine that you are
on a piece of code in a in your file and
you are working with URLs and you are
you know you you you practice something
that's maybe like you know URL encoding
or like you like ask the like the result
of the AI is giving you some code that's
related to that and you ask it to like
secure it right and it says okay let's
do URL encoding or the other way around
let's do URL decoding whatever like the
depends on like the current process
let's [clears throat] say let's say that
this is what it's suggests and by the
way that's that's probably one of the
things it should do so like that's a
proper process but what happens when it
is not aware that somewhere up the chain
right so I mean some you know let's say
this is your you know service and in
some other service you interact with or
you know the route the controller
whatever you know the the architecture
is you actually already did a URL
encoding so now you have double URL
encoding and that is potentially like a
security vulnerability like waiting to
happen due to the double encoding And so
if the LLM doesn't know to like trace
your code paths and say well well you
actually did an encoding before you
should not really reapply the encoding
because you could suffer the double
encoding injection then that's going to
get you busted. And so that's why it
needs more than being just a statistical
model and sometimes like vulnerabilities
in most of the cases honestly are very
nuanced and very complicated. While it's
sometimes easy to just you know
demonstrate some code injection, some
cross-ite scripting that we show in a
vulnerability and you know there it is.
It's it's usually most of the time
vulnerabilities are chained together.
They are more complicated. People you
know chain one to another like a
prototype pollution to do code injection
to do command injection to open a shell.
There's like a a layered approach when
things happen in the real world rather
than what we kind of you know demo.
We're going to jump into the second half
of our conversation, but first a quick
shout out to AI Native DevCon. Two days
of hands-on sessions, deep dives, and
honest conversations about what it means
to build AI software November 18th and
19th in New York or join virtually from
anywhere. Tickets and details at a
native.io/devcon.
See you there.
>> The maximum context size. Yeah,
>> you're just hitting that mark whereby
the results based on the amount of
context you provide degrades massively
significantly from from that.
>> Yes, the the this agent have um feature
called compaction.
>> Uh this basically tells the agent to
make a summary of all of the previous
conversation and start with the minimum
context from that summary. But the
problem is that the instructions that
are contained in the summary are half of
the ones that you instructed him
initially and um you have to um most
likely start from scratch again because
you don't know what he he misses.
>> Mhm. Okay. Okay. So what was what's
what's next in the in the spect?
>> So what what was next? The immediate
next step was to split the big markdown
file into smaller tasks. So I would have
similar to how you have in uh Jira or in
Lina or other project [music] management
tools single tasks that uh just define
what has to be built. And I basically
translated this into markdown files
because markdown is a universal language
that is plain text with formatting uh
that both humans and agents can uh
understand very well and agents were
actually more effective [music] and I
could easily roll back single tasks at
the time. And you did this manually or
you did this with
>> Yes, at the very beginning I was
creating manually and I uh when I
reached around 50 manual created tasks I
I was uh like any power software
engineer would try to automate this. How
can I automate this manual creation of
tasks? So I build backlog MD for uh
enabling this and have an easy way to
create task by uh using your terminal.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to
have a per user uh map, you know, and
I'm going to pass this chat memory
advisor.
Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> So, up. There we go. There we go. And
I'll go down here and then the advisor
the the map will say compute if absent
user,
right? And I'm just going to create a
new one if it doesn't exist and I'll
store it in memory. Now there's other
implementations of this chat memory
interface that you can use uh that will
write to different uh abstractions right
you can do like neo forj and JDBC and
>> I think there's one reddus coming along
I don't know all sorts of JDBC of course
you know all that stuff so okay this is
an advisor this is like a filter right
uh it's a pre-processor on the requests
intended for the model and basically as
we have a conversation with the model
this will get um stored per user in that
map and then it's a transcript in effect
of everything we said and that'll be
ret-ransmitted to the model on every
subsequent request so that the model
remembers oh we talked about AB and C
when the person asks about AB and C uh
remember it right so here we go so now
we go back and we say uh my name is Josh
>> great
>> what's my name your name is Josh fine
how do you do right so it's now got
memory uh but let's ask but this is
actually kind of a problem right like
which is a like Um, what's 2 + two,
right?
>> Yeah. Okay, great. But it's not supposed
to be helping people with their
homework. It's supposed to be a model to
help people adopt a dog. Clearly, we've
got we've kind of wandered off in the
deep end here.
>> And this is interesting because you see
a ton of companies. What was the what
was the the there was a couple of big
ones. I think one was it was iter or
someone where yeah it they were
basically getting it to to like write a
bunch of like malicious code and and
things like that from from the sites
which is kind of
>> Amazon for a moment I think their their
app they have an assistant there
>> and you can actually like
>> somebody prompted prompt poisoned it
yeah
>> and got it to like generate code for
them instead of helping them
>> with Amazon like
>> yeah anyway that's not what we want so
we don't want this thing getting too off
too far off in the weeds we have a
mission we want people to adopt dogs
>> unless you want it to know how many two
dogs plus another two dogs could be.
>> Right. So, what we want to do is uh is
to um give it a system prompt. The
system prompt is the overall tone and
tenor. So, var system.
>> Okay, here we are. And uh cat
desktop talk system. I happen to have a
system prompt. Okay, I'll paste that
there. Ah, you know what I just did that
felt wrong?
>> It's the wrong tool. It's the wrong one.
>> Yeah,
>> there. That's better. Do you know? Do
you know when you switched from cat to
Doug there? I was about to make that
joke and I thought, "Oh, no." The only
reason I know that joke is cuz you said
it last time I saw it a couple of months
ago.
>> I [laughter] love it. So, okay, that's
better. Right. So, we're going to say
you are an AI powered assistant to help
people adopt a dog from the adoption
agency called Pooch Palace with
locations in Ant, Seoul, Tokyo,
Singapore, Paris, Mumbai, Mumbai, New
Delhi, Barcelona, San Francisco, and
London. That's where we are in in
DevOuk. And uh information about the
dogs available will be presented below.
There's no information. Return a polite
response suggesting we don't have any
dogs available.